<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<search>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>今日份闲聊</title>
    <link href="/2022/12/23/%E4%BB%8A%E6%97%A5%E4%BB%BD%E9%97%B2%E8%81%8A/"/>
    <url>/2022/12/23/%E4%BB%8A%E6%97%A5%E4%BB%BD%E9%97%B2%E8%81%8A/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="TODAY’S-锅言锅语"><a href="#TODAY’S-锅言锅语" class="headerlink" title="TODAY’S 锅言锅语"></a>TODAY’S 锅言锅语</h1><p>今天老爸回来了，伙食明显改善了不少，也很难想象过去两天照顾老妈时我的垃圾厨艺是怎么养活两个人的。</p><p>晚上买了一个<strong>openAI</strong>的账号来玩玩，效果感觉一般，可能我的要求不够明确吧，或者说在数据科学那边OpenAI的效果更好。</p><h1 id="没了"><a href="#没了" class="headerlink" title="没了"></a><del>没了</del></h1><p>今天md又混了一天</p><p><u>26号考习概</u></p><p><u>31号物理网测结束前得把物理基础知识学完，md现在还啥都不会</u></p><h1 id="烦！烦！烦！"><a href="#烦！烦！烦！" class="headerlink" title="烦！烦！烦！"></a>烦！烦！烦！</h1>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>闲聊</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>随笔</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Glados_VPN</title>
    <link href="/2022/12/22/Glados-VPN/"/>
    <url>/2022/12/22/Glados-VPN/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="先上宝藏项目的链接"><a href="#先上宝藏项目的链接" class="headerlink" title="先上宝藏项目的链接"></a>先上宝藏项目的链接</h2><p><a href="https://github.com/sicilly/glados-checkin-1">GitHub - sicilly&#x2F;glados-checkin-1</a></p><p>该项目手把手教你注册Glados VPN教育优惠并如何使用作者的自动签到外挂，使其成为一个永久的<strong>免费白嫖</strong>梯子！</p><p>顺便附上Glados的官网：<a href="https://glados.rocks/">GLaDOS</a>，感谢你的教育优惠</p><h3 id="注意"><a href="#注意" class="headerlink" title="注意"></a>注意</h3><p>如果发现不可用，可能你没有从<a href="https://glados.rocks/console/account">GLaDOS</a>这个网址登陆并查看自己在该网站上account的cookie（因为glados有多个不同的顶级域.rocks&#x2F;.network&#x2F;.one等等，不同网址对应的account的cookie也不同）</p><h4 id="解决办法"><a href="#解决办法" class="headerlink" title="解决办法"></a>解决办法</h4><ol><li><p><u><strong>从.rocks这个网址登陆（因为开源项目作者大大的代码里使用的是这个网址）</strong></u></p></li><li><p><del>（不建议）自行在自己的仓库里修改代码，把作者大大代码中的相关url修改为自己当前登陆的网址</del></p></li></ol><h2 id="最后再膜拜一下作者大大，STAR了！"><a href="#最后再膜拜一下作者大大，STAR了！" class="headerlink" title="最后再膜拜一下作者大大，STAR了！"></a>最后再膜拜一下作者大大，STAR了！</h2><img src="/2022/12/22/Glados-VPN/pic1.png" class="">]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>宝藏项目</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>VPN</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>US adds 36 Chinese companies to trade blacklist</title>
    <link href="/2022/12/15/US-adds-36-Chinese-companies-to-trade-blacklist/"/>
    <url>/2022/12/15/US-adds-36-Chinese-companies-to-trade-blacklist/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<hr><p>The US has placed three dozen Chinese companies on a trade blacklist, in another escalation of its effort to slow China’s development of advanced chips and technologies for military uses such as hypersonic weapons.</p><p>The commerce department put 36 Chinese groups on the “entity list”, a move that means American companies will require extremely hard-to-obtain licences to export critical technologies to those customers in China.</p><p>It also applied the “foreign direct product rule” to 21 entities, meaning non-American companies will be prohibited from exporting products that contain a specified amount of US technology to the Chinese groups.</p><p>The dramatic action comes after Washington in October unveiled severe export controls designed to prevent China from developing high-end chips or producing the tools required to manufacture the chips domestically, as part of a growing effort to slow its military modernisation.</p><p>“We are building on the actions we took in October to protect US national security by severely restricting . . . China’s ability to leverage artificial intelligence, advanced computing and other powerful, commercially available technologies for military modernisation and human rights abuses,” said Alan Estevez, the top commerce department official for export controls.</p><p>The best-known target on the list is Yangtze Memory Technologies, China’s largest memory chip producer, which has been accused of violating US export controls by supplying Chinese telecom equipment maker Huawei, the Financial Times reported. </p><p>The commerce department said it targeted YMTC and a subsidiary in Japan because of “the risk of diversion”.</p><p>YMTC is not one of the 21 Chinese groups hit with the foreign direct product rule.<br>“I’ve long sounded the alarm on the grave national security and economic threats behind YMTC,” said Chuck Schumer, the top Senate Democrat. “YMTC poses an immediate threat to our national security so the . . . administration needed to act swiftly to prevent [it] from gaining even an inch of a military or economic advantage.”</p><p>Schumer has added an amendment to the 2023 defence spending bill that would ban the government from buying or using chips from China’s YMTC, Semiconductor Manufacturing International and ChangXin Memory Technologies. The Senate this week is expected to approve the massive $858bn defence bill, which has already passed the House.</p><p>One of the hardest hit groups was Cambricon, one of the leaders of a dynamic breed of chip design companies that has been driving the growth of China’s semiconductor and AI industries. The company and nine of its affiliates were placed on the entity list and also subjected to the foreign direct product rule.</p><p>Cambricon is a critical company in China’s domestic chip supply chain. One Cambricon engineer said the US export controls introduced in October had not affected the group much because their chip designs did not meet the target threshold.</p><p>However, the entity listing will create a major problem because it sources chip intellectual property from UK-based Arm and chip design tools from US makers Cadence and Synopsys. It also relies on Taiwan’s TSMC to produce the chips it designs.<br>The US also listed Tiandy, a surveillance camera and facial recognition software company, for allegedly facilitating the repression of China’s Uyghur minority and helping Iran obtain US technology.</p><p>Other companies added to the list include Chinese chip toolmaker Shanghai Micro Electronics Equipment Group and state-owned military suppliers such as AVIC Research Institute for Special Structures of Aeronautical Composites and affiliates of China Electronics Technology Group Corporation.</p><p>In addition, the US hit Shanghai Integrated Circuit Research and Development Center, a company backed by the Shanghai government that is involved in efforts to build domestic chips without using American technology. The group is also working with Huawei, which is already on the entity list based on concerns that it could facilitate Chinese espionage around the world.</p><p>In one welcome piece of news for China, the US removed 25 Chinese companies from the “unverified list” after it was able to determine they were not using US technology inappropriately.</p><p>When Washington unveiled its export controls in October, it added 31 Chinese companies to the unverified list and established a policy that set a 60-day clock for the Chinese commerce ministry and Chinese groups to allow the US to conduct end-use checks.</p><p>Matthew Axelrod, the top commerce official for enforcement, said the policy was “yielding results”. Beijing had for several years refused to allow end-use checks, partly as a result of the trade war that President Donald Trump launched against China in 2018.</p><p>The commerce department also placed nine Russian companies on the entity list because it was unable to complete end-use checks of the groups.<br>Follow Demetri Sevastopulo on Twitter</p><hr>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>news</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>finance</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>夜的呓语</title>
    <link href="/2022/12/14/%E5%A4%9C%E7%9A%84%E5%91%93%E8%AF%AD/"/>
    <url>/2022/12/14/%E5%A4%9C%E7%9A%84%E5%91%93%E8%AF%AD/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="就随意地记录一些最近的事情吧"><a href="#就随意地记录一些最近的事情吧" class="headerlink" title="就随意地记录一些最近的事情吧"></a>就随意地记录一些最近的事情吧</h2><p>xy前几天来找我聊天，我还是对“火”这东西有些敏感，又是寒假期间，毕竟之前自己也有过先例，不能再犯错，也听了骁的建议，发长文不如不回，就两天没回她，先断个火</p><p>今天xy来和我说羊了，既然火已经断了，就闲聊了一会儿，安慰了几句，不过聊天感觉状态也还挺好的。也顺带着加了微信，微信聊毕竟会正式些，比较不会有火不火啥的心理上的压力，也比较不会上头。</p><p>ysx他们也依旧还在对yw兴奋中，两天没打开wzry了，其实也没什么感觉，确实有些娱乐疲劳了。</p><p>后天开始有一个物理网测，还都不会。</p><p>26号还有xigai…………</p><h2 id="事已至此，先睡吧……"><a href="#事已至此，先睡吧……" class="headerlink" title="事已至此，先睡吧……"></a>事已至此，先睡吧……</h2>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>闲聊</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>随笔</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>TEST</title>
    <link href="/2022/12/13/TEST/"/>
    <url>/2022/12/13/TEST/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a TEST PAGE.</p><img src="/2022/12/13/TEST/head.jpg" class="" title="官方引用图片方法">]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>闲聊</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>原创</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Hello World</title>
    <link href="/2022/12/13/hello-world/"/>
    <url>/2022/12/13/hello-world/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to <a href="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</a>! This is your very first post. Check <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/">documentation</a> for more info. If you get any problems when using Hexo, you can find the answer in <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/troubleshooting.html">troubleshooting</a> or you can ask me on <a href="https://github.com/hexojs/hexo/issues">GitHub</a>.</p><h2 id="Quick-Start"><a href="#Quick-Start" class="headerlink" title="Quick Start"></a>Quick Start</h2><h3 id="Create-a-new-post"><a href="#Create-a-new-post" class="headerlink" title="Create a new post"></a>Create a new post</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">$ hexo new <span class="hljs-string">&quot;My New Post&quot;</span><br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/writing.html">Writing</a></p><h3 id="Run-server"><a href="#Run-server" class="headerlink" title="Run server"></a>Run server</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">$ hexo server<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/server.html">Server</a></p><h3 id="Generate-static-files"><a href="#Generate-static-files" class="headerlink" title="Generate static files"></a>Generate static files</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">$ hexo generate<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/generating.html">Generating</a></p><h3 id="Deploy-to-remote-sites"><a href="#Deploy-to-remote-sites" class="headerlink" title="Deploy to remote sites"></a>Deploy to remote sites</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">$ hexo deploy<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/one-command-deployment.html">Deployment</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  
</search>
